(The tassel crowns the knight.
The sword is snow white.)
(In the silver saddle,
he rides like a shooting star.)
(He kills a man within ten steps.
Invincible he is all the way ahead.)
(He would leave once it's done.
No trace of him is to be found.)
=Sword Snow Stride= (Season 1)
=Episode 5=
Look at the lake.
Is it beautiful?
The landscape falls into the lake.
The cloud is like crystal-clear frost.
It is
the best view in the world indeed.
It's not beautiful now.
It's beautiful with fish.
Where is the fish food?
Look!
Fish!
The golden scales break the blue sky.
It's more beautiful now.
It's not superlative.
The view at the center of the lake
is spectacular.
(Tingchao Pavilion)
(Propitious Omens)
(Imposing and Magnificent)
(Li Yishan, military counselor)
(Propitious Omens)
Stop here.
What to do now?
Spread the fish food.
Don't be so stingy.
This is the best view.
Don't you take a look?
You are from the Lin family
in Hedong, right?
Yes.
I trust you
about the assassination,
but people gossip.
Your family has to do something
to reassure North Liang.
Mr. Lin?
Your Highness,
you have a big appetite indeed.
Why are you acting like
a different person now?
Things change,
but I'm still who I am.
So, you've been acting.
If not,
how would you let your guard down?
If you don't let your guard down,
how would I have the chance
to be alone with you?
You want to kill me?
Yes.
I came here just to kill you.
What about Miss Fan?
I met her on the way here.
It's a godsend.
That slash of her sword
made you less defensive.
What will happen if you kill me?
If you die,
there will be no future
for the army of Xu!
That's it?
That's it.
I read sage books
to serve the people.
I'm willing to kill the culprit
for my country.
Are you not afraid
that she is a master of martial arts?
I'll take a chance!
You won.
That girl can't fight at all.
You won't
be able to live if you kill me.
What's there to be afraid
to die for my country?
Miss Fan will die, too.
Those who came here with you
will all die.
For the great cause,
one has no fear for sacrifice!
Do they know
that you will sacrifice them?
I'll make amends to them
in the hell!
I know you can't fight,
but I learned swordsmanship
from an early age.
Xu Fengnian.
That smile you just had
should be your last smile
in your life.
I smile
because I finally figure out
the purpose of the three assassinations,
and
who's behind all this.
What are you talking about?
No one orders me to kill you.
You are a pawn.
How would a pawn know
who is playing chess?
Xu Fengnian.
What a pity.
I'm a good swimmer.
Just die under the water!
I couldn't be happier.
I'm not going to save you.
I
Want to eat meat.
Thanks for coming down to save me.
Who...
Who wants to save you?
I want to see how you die.
I must let you down.
What is that thing
at the bottom of the lake?
I call him Old Hunk under the Lake.
Is it a person or a monster?
I guess it's a person.
No way.
How can a man live underwater?
In the first place,
he has strong internal force.
You know
people with strong internal force
have longer breathing intervals.
He still needs air.
There are fish in the lake.
But he's not a fish.
He eats living fish
and rips the swim bladder
from the fish's belly.
There's air inside the swim bladder.
That's how he stays alive.
There's not much air.
With strong internal force,
he doesn't need much air.
He kills a few more fish every day
and just gets through it.
Then when did you find him?
I fell into the lake when I was a child.
He saved my life.
Later, I often threw hot food
into the lake to feed him.
Gradually,
we got familiar.
So, you planned
where to park the boat?
Yeah.
You gave Mr. Lin a chance
to kill you on purpose.
That's right.
You never trusted him the whole time.
What you said and what you did
are just for testing him?
Why would I trust him?
So, you were also testing me
to see if I would join hands with him
in a crisis?
That's not what I meant.
Who knows when you are telling the truth
and when you are lying?
I swear in the name of my mother
that I have no intention of
testing Jiang Ni.
That would be the best.
But I didn't expect you
to jump into the lake to save me.
I said I wasn't trying to save you!
What are you doing?
My clothes are soaked.
It feels uncomfortable.
Stop taking off your clothes.
Keep your underclothes.
Rest assured.
I'm not that shameless.
You are already shameless.
How about you?
Are you not feeling uncomfortable?
I'm not uncomfortable.
I'm fine.
Your sleeves are wet.
I'll gouge your eyes out
if you keep looking at me!
Let's go.
Go by yourself.
I'll be back later.
Your clothes are all wet.
How improper it will be
if someone else sees you!
You walk ahead of me.
Does my back look good?
Very ugly.
Then why are you looking at it?
I'm not!
I jumped into the lake.
You didn't get guards for me,
but you brought me clothes?
Why do I feel
that I can't see through you,
Old Huang?
What's hard to see through me?
Can you stop chatting?
Just one more word.
Guess what I found?
Xu Fengnian!
Young Master.
I didn't let you go!
Wait.
Young Master.
Why did you jump down again?
What did you find?
A big fish?
Look.
I got it back for you.
I don't need it.
Old Huang.
I don't know what it is
and what's in it,
but I know
you've been carrying it with you
for years,
and it's important to you.
That's all in the past.
Why do you deny your past?
Your past
makes who you are now.
No matter what,
you're always Old Huang to me.
If you don't want it anymore
one day,
you need to tell me formally.
The wood is good.
I'll chop it
and roast a duck with it.
Since God wants you to find it,
don't use it to roast a duck.
I can't bear to let you do that.
Don't throw it away again.
I'll leave the man lying there to you.
No problem.
I'll take care of it, Young Master.
You are awake.
What's at the bottom of the lake?
It's my family's lake.
None of your business.
Kill me.
Don't think too much about it.
I'm here
to let you know
the consequences of this assassination.
The consequences?
Although I failed,
there will be other righteous men
coming after you.
No. Mr. Lin.
The Lin family is over.
It's my own decision to assassinate you.
What does it have to do
with my family?
You are the eldest son
of your family.
What do you think?
Isn't it over if I die?
Don't try to kill yourself.
It won't change the result
whether you die or not.
I just assassinated the son of
Lord of North Liang.
I'll get beheaded at worst.
My family won't be implicated.
What about the conspiracy of rebellion?
What rebellion?
The Lin family
colludes with the rebels in secret.
What else could it be
if it's not a rebellion?
There are no rebels!
You're trying to frame my family.
It's just your side of the story.
Who would believe you?
That's why
you have to be more careful
and cautious
when you do things,
so as not to be used as a pawn
and get your family exterminated
without knowing it.
You are talking nonsense
to throw me off balance.
Believe it or not.
Alright.
I'm done.
I'll leave.
Hold on!
What about Miss Fan?
She is in a woman's cell.
Would we lock her up with you?
I used her in this matter.
She has nothing to do with it.
It's too late.
She has been implicated by you.
Xu Fengnian!
I know you are a righteous man,
but have you thought about
that you might have gone too far?
I don't even know your name.
Never mind.
It's not important.
It's impossible.
He was just trying to scare me.
Xu Fengnian!
Why are you still on the first floor?
I'm reading books.
But there are introductory books
on martial arts on this floor.
You don't need them anymore.
To be the best in the world,
I need to learn from the ground up.
Good luck.
I'll go to see someone.
Your Grandpa Wei
is sleeping in the back.
I'm not looking for him.
I want to see my master.
Didn't you say you couldn't face him
until you unravel
the whole assassination event?
I unraveled it.
You know who's trying to kill you?
I know
who is behind the scenes,
but his purpose
is not to kill me.
The three assassinations
all happened in Lingzhou,
but the result he wants
is thousands of miles away.
I'll tell you in detail later.
That's not necessary.
If it's not about martial arts,
I'm not interested anyway.
I'm leaving.
Master.
I'm back.
Did you unravel
the whole assassination event?
Yes.
Who planned it?
Zhao Heng,
the Lord of Jing'an in Qingzhou.
Be more specific.
In the first round of assassination,
the remaining troops of Chu assembled.
I believe
the Lord of Jing'an must be
the driving force behind it.
In the second round of assassination,
Yu Youwei is the daughter
of a swordsman from the Chu.
She acted like she wanted
to avenge her lost country.
Xu Xiao annihilated the Chu.
Who else should I kill but you?
Zhao Heng kept Yu Youwei
for such a day.
Lin initiated
the third round of assassination,
which is the most important round.
(Noodles)
He wants to kill me
because he believes
that North Liang endangers the country.
But all this
can't be done
without Zhao Heng,
being the driving force behind it.
What's the evidence?
There isn't any evidence.
Even Lin himself wouldn't know
that he wants to kill me
because he was subtly influenced
by the Lord of Jing'an.
What are you talking about?
No one orders me to kill you.
Once Lin made a move,
everyone would think
that the Lin family joined hands
with the Chu veterans,
and what he did
became treasonous in nature.
So,
the Lin family is over.
Then why would Zhao Heng
try to make all of this happen?
Qingzhou is one of the key areas
to defend against North Liang.
(Qingzhou)
Zhao Heng commands Qingzhou
and controls the Navy.
You can say
(Lingzhou)
that he grabs North Liang by the throat.
But he did contend
for the throne before.
The court doesn't trust him.
That's why it has been
the Lin family in Hedong
who has the fiscal control of Qingzhou.
After three rounds of assassination,
the Lin family would fall into
the whirlpool of treason.
They can't be saved.
After that,
the fall of the Lin family
would leave the Lord of Jing'an
in sole control of Qingzhou.
No one can play against him anymore.
He planned all this
not to kill me,
but
to take full control of Qingzhou.
A series of lethal moves.
The real game
is outside the chessboard.
The cause and effect
are thousands of miles apart.
The Lord of Jing'an, Zhao Heng,
is a scary player indeed.
What if you get killed?
If I die,
North Liang would be in chaos.
It would do good to Qingzhou.
The Lord of Jing'an would win anyway
in this game.
You haven't seen through
this game.
Who are you?
I am the usurper.
Look.
I'm standing right in front of you.
You don't even know who I am.
Xu Xiao?
Actually,
I kind of appreciate you.
You want to persuade me to surrender?
Xu Xiao.
It can only happen in your dream
to make me serve a usurper.
You are so righteous.
I'm embarrassed to keep lying to you.
What do you want to say?
Come in!
Brother Lin.
Miss Fan.
Xu Xiao!
It has nothing to do with her!
Brother Lin.
Did they release you?
I lied to you.
You can hit me
and scold me.
I deserve it.
I'm not wronged.
We are all acting.
Did I do a good job?
You...
Lin.
Do you really think
we met by accident?
I had her
waiting for you
on the way
when you left your mansion.
Why?
First of all,
the assassination
entered
the third round.
I must let her give you a push
at the crucial moment.
Second,
my son must find out
who Qingniao is.
Therefore,
she must wield her sword.
How hard it is for me to be a father.
I have to find a way
to give my son what he wants.
Am I right?
What's more,
with my words,
it would be set in stone
that the Lin family
colludes with the Chu survivors.
There is no chance
to turn the tide.
Xu Xiao!
You treacherous man!
The planning is done.
I have told you the truth.
Regard it
as my respect for your righteousness.
Shu Xiu!
Grand Commander.
Send a message to Wang Linquan
that
the Lin family is over.
Make sure he will destroy
the lifeblood of the Lin family
step by step.
Zhao Heng has always wanted
to destroy the Lin family
and dominate Qingzhou, right?
Good.
Let's give him a hand.
The Lord of Jing'an doesn't know
that although the Lin family falls,
his henchman who will take over
Qingzhou's fiscal power
is actually
from North Liang
who has been planted
by his side long ago.
This is a good game
indeed.
Go ahead.
I need to thank you
for this whole thing.
Your name is Lin...
Lin...
Never mind. It doesn't matter.
You mean Xu Xiao has been prepared
for this game?
It's more than that.
Could there be a deeper layer?
You must always keep in mind
that what you need to see
is not just the game,
but also
the secret plan of the chess player.
I think you know the deepest dungeon
in the mansion.
Yes.
Go there and take a look.
Maybe you'll understand.
Access to the deepest level
requires Xu Xiao's warrant.
I don't have it.
This will do.
What do you want me to see?
What else could it be?
It's a person.
Someone you know.
Show your warrant.
Why are you here?
Did you forget
it was you who gave the order?
Soldier!
Put this rebel
in jail!
But I've set you free.
I'm afraid you got it wrong.
Ning Emei is an honest man.
Make up an excuse
and release him.
Do you know Lin?
Who?
You don't know him.
You have nothing to do
with the Lin family's operation.
Did you ask Yu Youwei to assassinate me?
If you want to kill me,
just do it.
Why bother to fabricate a charge on me?
You have nothing to do with Yu Youwei.
Could it be outside Lingzhou...?
No.
It was you
who showed up in time
and saved me from the Chu people.
You have nothing to do
with three assassinations.
Why are you here?
On the lowest floor of the dungeon?
You are also here.
Dig deeper.
Okay.
Leave us.
You want to see me?
Why is Ning Emei
still locked up in the dungeon?
It's something I shouldn't know?
You'll know it sooner or later.
I didn't tell you
because
I don't want
to put you in that position.
Is it a big deal?
Do you know
where our greatest enemy is?
North Mang?
Not there.
The capital?
The royal clan
is indeed wary of North Liang,
but they are still
foreign enemies.
You mean
North Liang's greatest enemy
is inside of us?
That's right.
The North Liang Cavalry
is unparalleled in the world.
The only way to destroy
the foundation of North Liang
is to start from
the inside.
Does Ning Emei
collude with foreign enemies?
No.
Is he plotting a rebellion?
He is loyal.
Then why did you lock him up?
He supports your younger brother.
What did you say?
Get up.
- Bravo!
Huangman'er
was born with great strength.
He has
plenty of supporters in the army.
Isn't it a good thing?
There are even people
supporting him
to take over military power
and rule North Liang.
Ning Emei is one of them?
So, you're going to kill him yourself
to stabilize the army.
Just for that?
Wait,
they want your younger brother
to take your place.
What's wrong with
letting him take my place?
I don't want it anyway.
Do you know
why they support him?
You just said yourself
that Huangman'er was born
with great strength.
But he has the mind of a child.
The royal clan is coveting North Liang.
There are countless foreign enemies.
How do you expect your brother
to take control over
such a situation?
Those who support him
don't know that?
Why do they choose Huangman'er?
Just because
he is naive
and easy to control.
If
Your little brother
takes over North Liang,
he will become
a pawn of those schemers.
When that day comes,
the Xu family
will be doomed.
Ning Emei doesn't look like a schemer.
He certainly wasn't trying
to control your brother.
He just
admires Huangman'er.
Men like him in the army
are pawns
put on the surface by those people.
Then who are the people
trying to take this chance
to control North Liang?
I'm still looking into it.
No hurry.
Kill Ning Emei first.
That will be a wake-up call for them.
But I need a charge to kill Ning Emei.
The assassination
of Lord of North Liang's son.
There are only words
without evidence.
Who would believe it?
If I kill Ning Emei like this,
it will undermine
the morale of the army.
Who said there is no evidence?
Do you remember
someone sent your portrait
to the bandits
in the first round of assassination?
I'll find out
about the portrait for you.
He colluded with foreign enemies.
It's a crime deserving
the death penalty.
Was it really Ning Emei
who sent out the portrait?
Is it that important
whether he did it or not?
Who gave the portrait to the Chu people?
You gave them the portrait?
Look.
Look at it.
I picked one
The Lord of Jing'an
plotted assassinations
for the fiscal power of Qingzhou,
and you played along
to root out dissenters.
Ning Emei also
has supporters in the army.
As long as we convict him
of collusion with the enemy,
we can kill him.
Even he's innocent?
North Liang can't be in chaos.
We have to kill him
to stabilize the army.
North Liang can't be in chaos.
That's also what Chen Zhibao said.
He also knows it, right?
You're my oldest son.
What we did
is for your good.
I won't kill Ning Emei.
Fengnian.
Your last name is Xu.
To protect North Liang
is one of
your inherent responsibilities.
So, I can kill innocent people
for the sake of North Liang?
I won't kill Ning Emei.
Okay.
You don't have to kill him.
There's a second option.
If
Huangman'er is gone,
there will be
no fight over power anymore.
Do you know what you're talking about?
That's not what I meant.
Even a vicious tiger
will not eat its cubs.
What do you mean by he is gone?
Make Huangman'er leave North Liang.
Enough!
Whether you kill Ning Emei
to punish those ambitious men
in the army,
or I send Huangman'er away
to solve this problem for good.
You have to make a choice.
I'm not going to choose either one.
North Liang occupies
the land of three states
and commands
the cavalry of 350,000 soldiers.
To guard such a vast land,
how can you not get blood on your hands?
That's why I said
I never wanted it!
What about North Liang's future?
Don't they call Chen Zhibao
the Little Slayer?
He is the ideal person!
I've made myself clear.
Huangman'er can't leave.
Ning Emei can't be killed.
So be it.
♪ The flower of pain ♪